Let's tackle the tidiness issues now,
现在 我们来处理整洁问题
and there are a few in this dataset.
该数据集中有几个这样的问题
Recall that this is the other way that data can be unclean.
回想一下 这是数据不整洁的另一种呈现方式
Data can be low quality or dirty and it can be untidy or messy.
数据可能是质量低或不干净且可能不整洁或杂乱
So with quality previously in this lesson,
对于本课前面提到的质量而言
it was issues with our data's content that we were looking for.
这是我们正在寻找的数据内容存在的问题
And now with tidiness it's structural issues.
现在整洁度其实是结构问题
Having tidy data makes our data easier to analyze in most cases.
拥有整洁的数据 大多数情况下会使数据分析会变得更轻松
And it also makes cleaning easier as per both of these documents by Hadley Wickham,
另外 遵循 Hadley Wickham 的这两份文件清理会变得更容易
the creator of the tidy data format.
Hadley Wickham 是整洁数据格式的创始人
Regarding making data cleaning easier,
在本课程的下一课
you'll see how this is true in the next lesson in this course which is on cleaning,
你将学习如何使数据清理变得更容易 下一课的主题是清理
the third step in the data wrangling process.
即 数据整理过程的第三步
Let's go over what tidy data actually is again.
我们再来复习一下整洁数据实际指什么
There are three requirements for tidiness.
对整洁度有三个要求
Each variable forms a column,
每个变量构成一列
each observation forms a row,
每项观察构成一行
and each type of observational unit forms a table.
每种类型的观察单元构成一个表格
So let's start by assessing for tidiness by assessing visually directly in Pandas here.
我们开始吧 在这里的 Pandas 中直接目测评估整洁度
So we've got a patients table, a treatment table,
在本次临床试验数据集中
and an adverse reactions table in this clinical trial data set.
我们已获得患者表、治疗表和不良反应表各一份
In this patients table this contact column
在患者表中 我认为 联系人列
is the most glaring tidiness issue in my opinion.
出现了最显著的整洁度问题
There are two variables in one column which
一列中有两个变量
violates the "each variable forms a column" requirement.
这违反了“每个变量构成一列”的要求
There is phone number and also e-mail address in this contact column.
此联系人列中同时有电话号码和电子邮件地址
These should be split into two separate columns just
这些变量应该像这样分为两个单独的列
like this and that's how the record for Zoe Wellish would be filled out.
这就是填写有关 Zoe Wellish 的记录方式
That was done using manual cleaning which
这是手动清理完成的 再次声明
again we shouldn't use unless it's one-off occurrences.
除非它是一次性事件 否则我们不该使用手动清理
And in this column it's definitely not one-off occurrences.
在此列中 它绝对不是一次性事件
You'll write code to automate this cleaning
你要编写代码使该清理自动化
leveraging a cleaning tool called regular expressions in the next lesson.
利用下一课中称为正则表达式的清理工具清理
It's a pretty amazing tool that's really flexible.
这是一个非常棒的工具 非常灵活
Okay so that's one, let's document that issue right now.
好的 这个问题说到这 现在我们来记录那个问题
And once again I'd like to separate the issues by quality and tidiness when documenting.
再次 我想在记录时按质量和整洁度对问题进行分类
So we'll put this one
于是 我们将这个问题归为
under tidiness.
整洁度问题
Let's move on now.
我们现在继续
Back to the visual assessment part of our Jupyter Notebook.
回到我们的 Jupyter Notebook 的目测评估部分
So this treatment's table is untidy too.
该治疗表也不整洁
And these Auralin and Novodra columns are the offenders.
而且 Auralin 列和 Novodra 列都是违规的
Again these have dosage information in each entry in each column.
此外 这些列在每列的每个条目中都有剂量信息
What tidy data rule or rules do these columns
这些列打破了整洁数据的哪条或哪些规则
break and how should these two columns be re-represented in a tidy format?
且这两列应当如何以整洁的格式重新表示？